Elihu Vedder
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1804-1951, Series 2:; (Boxes 2-5; 3.6 linear feet)
  - Correspondence, February 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1307-1351)
  - Correspondence, March-May 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1352-1394)
  - Correspondence, June 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1395-1413)
  - Correspondence, July 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1414-1477)
  - Correspondence, August 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1478-1527)
  - Correspondence, September-November 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1528-1581)
  - Correspondence, December 1900 (Reel 522, Frame 1582-1632)
  - Correspondence, 1-20 January 1901 (Reel 522, Frame 1633-1661)
  - Correspondence, 22 January-February 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 1-50)
  - Correspondence, March 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 51-111)
  - Correspondence, April 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 112-165)
  - Correspondence, May 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 166-235)
  - Correspondence, 1-8 June 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 236-269)
  - Correspondence, 9-30 June 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 270-322)
  - Correspondence, August-October 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 323-355)
  - Correspondence, November-December 1901 (Reel 523, Frame 356-381)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1902 (Reel 523, Frame 382-413)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1902 (Reel 523, Frame 414-445)
  - Correspondence, 1-14 January 1903 (Reel 523, Frame 446-497)
  - Correspondence, 15-31 January 1903 (Reel 523, Frame 498-540)
  - Correspondence, February 1903 (Reel 523, Frame 541-578)
  - Correspondence, March-April 1903 (Reel 523, Frame 579-610)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1903 (Reel 523, Frame 611-665)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Reel 2323, Frame 360-361)
  - Correspondence, January-October 1904 (Reel 523, Frame 666-702)
  - Correspondence, November 1904 (Reel 523, Frame 703-747)
  - Correspondence, December 1904 (Reel 523, Frame 748-792)
  - Correspondence, 1904 (Reel 2323, Frame 362-363)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 793-814)
  - Correspondence, 1-7 May 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 815-871)
  - Correspondence, 8-17 May 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 872-926)
  - Correspondence, 18-25 May 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 927-962)
  - Correspondence, 26-31 May 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 963-1005)
  - Correspondence, 1-8 June 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 1006-1059)
  - Correspondence, 9-17 June 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 1060-1101)
  - Correspondence, 18-30 June 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 1102-1151)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1905 (Reel 523, Frame 1152-1182)
  - Correspondence, 1905 (Reel 2323, Frame 364-365)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1906 (Reel 523, Frame 1183-1220)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1906 (Reel 523, Frame 1221-1278)
  - Correspondence, 1906 (Reel 2323, Frame 366-368)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1907 (Reel 523, Frame 1279-1327)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1907 (Reel 523, Frame 1328-1396)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1908 (Reel 523, Frame 1397-1416)
  - Correspondence, April 1908 (Reel 523, Frame 1417-1487)
  - Correspondence, May 1908 (Reel 523, Frame 1488-1564)
  - Correspondence, 1-25 June 1908 (Reel 523, Frame 1565-1615)
  - Correspondence, 25 June-December 1908 (Reel 524, Frame 1-21)
  - Correspondence, 1909 (Reel 524, Frame 22-75)
  - Correspondence, 1909 (Reel 2323, Frame 369-372)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Reel 524, Frame 77-153)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Reel 2323, Frame 373-378)
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Reel 524, Frame 154-161)
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Reel 2323, Frame 379-382)
  - Correspondence, 1912 (Reel 524, Frame 162-172)
  - Correspondence, 1912 (Reel 2323, Frame 383-385)
  - Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Reel 524, Frame 173-190)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Reel 2323, Frame 386-390)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1919 (Reel 524, Frame 191-212)
  - Correspondence, 1915, 1919 (Reel 2323, Frame 391-392)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1923 (Reel 524, Frame 213-226)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Reel 2323, Frame 393-395)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Reel 524, Frame 227-234)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Reel 2323, Frame 396-402)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Reel 524, Frame 235-248)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1937 (Reel 524, Frame 249-263)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Reel 524, Frame 264-310)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1951 (Reel 524, Frame 311-335)
  - Correspondence A, undated (Reel 524, Frame 338-383)
  - Correspondence B, undated (Reel 524, Frame 384-432)
  - Correspondence, Butler, Annie, undated, (1 of 5) (Reel 524, Frame 434-474)
  - Correspondence, Butler, Annie, undated, (2 of 5) (Reel 524, Frame 475-529)
  - Correspondence, Butler, Annie, undated, (3 of 5) (Reel 524, Frame 530-586)
  - Correspondence, Butler, Annie, undated, (4 of 5) (Reel 524, Frame 587-625)
  - Correspondence, Butler, Annie, undated, (5 of 5) (Reel 524, Frame 626-670)
  - Correspondence, C, undated (Reel 524, Frame 671-719)
  - Correspondence, D-E, undated (Reel 524, Frame 720-750)
  - Correspondence, F-G, undated (Reel 524, Frame 765-822)
  - Correspondence, Ha-Hep, undated (Reel 524, Frame 823-888)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (1 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 751-764)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (2 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 890-947)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (3 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 948-1000)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (4 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 1001-1059)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (5 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 1060-1117)
  - Correspondence, Herriman, Elizabeth, undated, (6 of 6) (Reel 524, Frame 1118-1164)
  - Correspondence, Hi-K, undated (Reel 524, Frame 1166-1194)
  - Correspondence, L, undated (Reel 524, Frame 1195-1272)
  - Correspondence, M, undated, (1 of 2) (Reel 524, Frame 1273-1312)
  - Correspondence, M, undated, (2 of 2) (Reel 524, Frame 1313-1369)
  - Correspondence, N-P, undated (Reel 524, Frame 1370-1385)
  - Correspondence, R, undated, (1 of 3) (Reel 524, Frame 1386-1433)
  - Correspondence, R, undated, (2 of 3) (Reel 524, Frame 1434-1477)
  - Correspondence, R, undated, (3 of 3) (Reel 524, Frame 1478-1512)
  - Correspondence, S, undated, (1 of 2) (Reel 524, Frame 1513-1571)
  - Correspondence, S, undated, (2 of 2) (Reel 524, Frame 1572-1621)
  - Correspondence, T, undated (Reel 524, Frame 1622-1685)
  - Correspondence, Va-Ved, undated (Reel 524, Frame 1686-1697)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Anita H., undated (Reel 525, Frame 2-73)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline E., undated (Reel 525, Frame 75-80)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (1 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 82-136)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (2 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 137-187)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (3 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 188-247)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (4 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 248-292)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (5 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 293-328)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Caroline R., undated, (6 of 6) (Reel 525, Frame 329-376)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Elihu, undated, (1 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 378-422)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Elihu, undated, (2 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 423-475)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Elihu, undated, (3 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 476-532)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Elihu, undated, (4 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 533-599)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Elihu, Sr., undated (Reel 525, Frame 601-609)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Enoch, undated, (1 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 611-662)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Enoch, undated, (2 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 663-712)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Enoch, undated, (3 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 713-764)
  - Correspondence, Vedder, Enoch, undated, (4 of 4) (Reel 525, Frame 765-811)
  - Correspondence, W, undated (Reel 525, Frame 813-848)
  - Correspondence, Unidentified, undated, (1 of 3) (Reel 525, Frame 849-913)
  - Correspondence, Unidentified, undated, (2 of 3) (Reel 526, Frame 1-44)
  - Correspondence, Unidentified, undated, (3 of 3) (Reel 526, Frame 45-95)
  - Correspondence, Unidentified, undated (Reel 2323, Frame 6-28)
  - Correspondence, A-H, undated (Reel 2323, Frame 30-62)
  - Correspondence, I-R, undated (Reel 2323, Frame 63-108)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, undated (Reel 2323, Frame 109-126)
- Diaries, 1878-1890, Series 3:; (Box 5; 0.1 folders)
  Series consists of several diaries belonging to Caroline R. Vedder and Elihu Vedder. Caroline Vedder's diaries record daily activities in the Vedder household during 1878 and her travels in the United States in 1882. Vedder's diaries record his trip down the Nile in 1889-1890 and include some sketches.
  - Daily Diary (Caroline R. Vedder), 1878 (Reel 526, Frame 98-189)
  - Travel Notes (Caroline R. Vedder), 1882 (Reel 526, Frame 191-195)
  - Travel Diary (Elihu Vedder), 1889-1890 (Reel 526, Frame 197-270)
  - Nile Journey and Dates (Elihu Vedder), 1889-1890 (Reel 526, Frame 272-278)
- Writings, 1848-1923, 1969, Series 4:; (Boxes 5-7, 10; 1.7. linear feet)
  This series consists of drafts, manuscripts, typescripts, and illustrations for various books that Vedder wrote late in his career after he had stopped painting, including his autobiographical book, The Digressions of V (1910), and his books of verses, Miscellaneous Moods (privately printed in 1915), Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing (seemingly never published), and Doubt and Other Things (1922). Also found are drafts and manuscripts of various poems, essays, and stories, some of which may have been incorporated into his books, as well as notebooks and fragments; and some writings by others, including poems by Henry W. Austin, Florinda Brown, and others, and a copy of Nola Tutag's dissertation on Vedder, "A Reconstruction of the Career of Elihu Vedder" (1969).
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (1 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 361-410)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (2 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 411-456)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (3 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 457-504)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (4 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 505-542)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (5 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 543-621)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (6 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 622-667)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (7 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 668-708)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (8 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 709-759)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (9 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 760-818)
  - The Digressions of V, Loose Manuscripts, circa 1910, (10 of 10) (Reel 526, Frame 819-877)
  - The Digressions of V, Manuscripts, circa 1910, (bound volume) (Reel 526, Frame 878-1059)
  - The Digressions of V, Typescripts, circa 1910, (3 folders) (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Manuscript, circa 1922, (bound volume) (Reel 526, Frame 1061-1208)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (1 of 7) (Reel 527, Frame 1-71)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (2 of 7) (Reel 527, Frame 72-122)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (3 of 7) (Reel 527, Frame 123-182)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (4 of 7) (Reel 527, Frame 183-207)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (5 of 7; partially microfilmed) (Reel 527, Frame 208-265)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (6 of 7; partially microfilmed) (Reel 527, Frame 266-314)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (7 of 7) (Reel 527, Frame 315-321)
  - Doubt and Other Things, Set of Stage Proofs, circa 1922 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Manuscripts, 1907-1910, undated, (1 of 5) (Reel 527, Frame 323-370)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Manuscripts, 1907-1910, undated, (2 of 5) (Reel 527, Frame 371-423)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Manuscripts, 1907-1910, undated, (3 of 5) (Reel 527, Frame 424-477)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Manuscripts, 1907-1910, undated, (4 of 5) (Reel 527, Frame 478-533)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Manuscripts, 1907-1910, undated, (5 of 5) (Reel 527, Frame 534-581)
  - "Thoughts While Dressing and Undressing," Typescript Copy, undated (Reel 527, Frame 582-660)
  - Stories, 1872-1913, undated, (1 of 2) (Reel 527, Frame 662-711)
  - Stories, 1872-1913, undated, (2 of 2) (Reel 527, Frame 712-769)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (1 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 771-825)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (2 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 826-888)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (3 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 889-941)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (4 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 942-993)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (5 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 994-1047)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (6 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 1048-1101)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (7 of 16; partially microfilmed) (Reel 527, Frame 1102-1135)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (8 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 1136-1186)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (9 of 16; partially microfilmed) (Reel 527, Frame 1187-1233)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (10 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 1234-1287)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (11 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 1288-1337)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (12 of 16) (Reel 527, Frame 1338-1406)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (13 of 16) (Reel 528, Frame 1-52)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (14 of 16; partially microfilmed) (Reel 528, Frame 53-109)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (15 of 16) (Reel 528, Frame 110-163)
  - Poems and Essays, circa 1907-1923, (16 of 16) (Reel 528, Frame 164-228)
  - Notebook, 1915 (Reel 528, Frame 230-313)
  - Notebook, undated (Reel 528, Frame 354-368)
  - Fragments, 1909-1914, undated, (1 of 3) (Reel 528, Frame 314-353)
  - Fragments, 1909-1914, undated, (2 of 3) (Reel 528, Frame 369-424)
  - Fragments, 1909-1914, (3 of 3; partially microfilmed) (Reel 528, Frame 425-496)
  - Poems by Henry W. Austin and Others, 1848-1895, (1 of 2) (Reel 526, Frame 281-307)
  - Poems by Henry W. Austin and Others, 1848-1895, (2 of 2) (Reel 526, Frame 308-359)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (1 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 438-488)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (2 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 489-539)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (3 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 540-590)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (4 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 591-640)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (5 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 641-710)
  - Dissertation on Elihu Vedder by Nola Tutag, 1969, (6 of 6) (Reel 529, Frame 711-749)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings (by others?), undated (Reel 2323, Frame 406-421)
  - Oversize, Doubt and Other Things, Typescripts and Illustrations, circa 1922, (see also Box 10; see Reel 527: 266-314)
- Books and Printed Material, 1864-1939, Series 5:; (Boxes 7-8; 0.9 linear feet)
  This series consists of Vedder's published books, clippings (concerning his artwork, exhibitions, and published works, and obituaries for family and friends), exhibition catalogs, various catalogs with works by Vedder, reproductions of Vedder's artwork, uncut copies of his printed story, "The Story of Medusa," and an announcement of Vedder's first prize in the Christmas Card Competition held by L. Prang and Company.
  - Books (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - The Digressions of V, Volume I, Autograph Copy Number 199,1910 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - The Digressions of V, Volume II, 1910 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - Miscellaneous Moods, Limited Edition, 1915 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
    - Doubt and Other Things, 1922 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Clippings, 1864-1899 (Reel 528, Frame 1047-1100)
  - Clippings, 1900-1923, (partially microfilmed) (Reel 528, Frame 1101-1152)
  - Clippings, 1924-1937 (Reel 529, Frame 0-9)
  - Clippings, undated, (1 of 4) (Reel 529, Frame 10-59)
  - Clippings, undated, (2 of 4) (Reel 529, Frame 60-112)
  - Clippings, undated, (3 of 4; partially microfilmed) (Reel 529, Frame 113-154)
  - Clippings, undated, (4 of 4; partially microfilmed) (Reel 529, Frame 155-189)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1901-1929 (Reel 529, Frame 190-227)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1930-1937 (Reel 529, Frame 228-277)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1937 (Reel 529, Frame 278-325)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1938 (Reel 529, Frame 326-384)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1939, undated (Reel 529, Frame 385-392)
  - Catalogs, 1899-1903, undated, (3 folders; partially microfilmed) (Reel 529, Frame 394-436)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1889, undated (Reel 2323, Frame 422-432)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, undated (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Color Reproductions of Artwork, undated (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Copies of "The Story of Medusa," 1872 (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Announcement of First Prize Christmas Card by Elihu Vedder, 1881? (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
- Drawings, 1888-1912, Series 6:; (Box 8, OV 12; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series includes scattered drawings by Elihu Vedder, including a floor plan of his studio and other plans, sketches of cups, vases, and a wall display, copies of various bookplates (which may or may not have been designed by Vedder), and six original drawings, four of which are on microfilm only.
  - Plans, Sketches, and Bookplates, 1888-1912, undated (Reel 529, Frame 751-768)
  - Oversize, Drawings, Study for "The Rubaiyat" and "The Artist's Daughter," undated, (see OV 12; four of six drawings on microfilm only) (Reel 671, Frame 608-613)
- Photographs, 1840s-1920s, Series 7:; (Boxes 8-9, 11, OV 13; 1.5 linear feet)
  This series consists primarily of photographs of Vedder, his studio, his family and friends, and his artwork, including tintypes, 11 daguerreotypes, cartes-de-visite, cabinet cards, and silver gelatin, albumen, and platinum prints. Photographs of Vedder include a portrait of him as a young boy (daguerreotype), portraits of him as a young man and later in life, and ones of him in his studio (including in his San Basilio studio). Family photos include ones of Vedder's wife, Caroline R. Vedder, and children, Philip, Enoch and Anita; ones of Vedder with his wife and children, ones of Vedder and his wife with her family around the time they were married; and ones of Vedder's and Caroline R. Vedder's extended families (many of these can be found in Caroline R. Vedder's cartes-de-visite album, which was disassembled at some point after microfilming). Photos of friends include ones of Charles Caryl Coleman, Kate Field, and Amelia B. Edwards, and ones of Vedder and George Simonds in costume.
  Other photos include: ones from a trip to America in 1901, ones of various residences (including the Vedder home outside St. Augustine, Florida and Vedder's villa in Italy), ones from an unidentified exhibition of Vedder's artwork, and various snapshots (including Italian scenes, and views from a hotel window in Pittsburgh and a from a window in St. Augustine.
  This series has been scanned from the original photographs rather than microfilm. Items not scanned include photographs artwork and duplicates.
  - Photographs of Elihu Vedder, circa 1860s-1920s, (4 folders; oversized items housed in Box 11, Folders 1-2) (Box 8, Folder 7-10)
  - Portrait of Elihu Vedder, Hand-Colored Photographic Print of Painting, "Artist's Studio" by Charles Coleman, circa 1900, (Oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 3) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Elihu Vedder, Duplicates, circa 1890s-1920s, (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Family, Daguerreotypes, 1840s-1860s (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Family, Copy Prints of Daguerreotypes, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Caroline R. Vedder's Carte-de-Visite Album, late 1800s, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 15-20)
  - Photographs of Caroline R. Vedder, circa 1869-1880s, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - Photographs of Caroline R. Vedder, Duplicates, 1880s, (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Philip Vedder, early 1870s (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Enoch Vedder, 1870s-1910 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Anita Vedder, 1880s-1890s, (Oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 4) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Family, 1850s-1890s, (3 folders; oversized items housed in Box 11, Folders 5-6) (Box 8, Folder 27-29)
  - Photographs from Trip to America, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Photograph Album, San Basilio Studio and Viareggio, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Photographs of Friends, 1880s-early 1900s, (3 folders; oversized items housed in OV 13) (Box 8, Folder 32-34)
  - Photographs of Elihu Vedder and George Simonds in Costume, circa 1870, (2 folders; oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 7) (Box 8, Folder 35-36)
  - Photographs of Unidentified People, late 1800s-early 1900s (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Various Residences, Interiors and Exteriors, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Elihu Vedder's Villa in Italy, 1907, (Oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 8) (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Various Snaphots, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 40-42)
  - Exhibition Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Photograph of Vedder Fountain, undated, (Oversized items housed in OV 13) (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (6 folders; not scanned; oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 9 and OV 13) (Box 9 (hol), Folder 1-6)
  - Photographs of Works of Art by Others, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 9 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Duplicates, undated, (2 folders; not scanned; oversized items housed in Box 11, Folder 10) (Box 9 (hol), Folder 8-9)
  - Negatives, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 9 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Elihu Vedder, circa 1860s-1920s, (2 folders; Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 10) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 1-2)
  - Portrait of Elihu Vedder, Hand-Colored Photographic Print of Painting, "Artist's Studio" by Charles Coleman, circa 1900, (Item scanned with Box 8, Folder 11) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Anita Vedder, 1880s-1890s, (Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 26) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 4)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Family, 1850s-1890s, (2 folders; Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 29) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 5-6)
  - Oversize, Photograph of Elihu Vedder and George Simonds in Costume, circa 1870, (Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 36) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 7)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Elihu Vedder's Villa in Italy, 1907, (Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 39) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 8)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (see also Box 9, Folders 1-6, OV 13; not scanned) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 9)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Works of Art, Duplicates, undated, (see also Box 9, Folders 8-9; not scanned) (Box 11 (sol), Folder 10)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Friends, 1880s-early 1900s, (Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 34) (Box OV 13)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Vedder Fountain, undated, (Items scanned with Box 8, Folder 44) (Box OV 13)
  - Oversize, Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (see also Box 9, Folders 1-6, Box 11; not scanned) (Box OV 13)